再排一次
Let's rehearse again everybody!
关大门
Shut the gate.
集中注意力
Concentrate please!
都准备好了？
Ready everybody?!
进攻
Attack!
快动啊 进攻
Well go on! Attack!
够了你们
That's enough everybody.
蠢蛋们 都住手
Stop you idiots.
停下
Stop!
你们知不知道 这戏得花多少银子？嗯？
Have you any idea of the cost of this production?Hmm?
你们真的妄想 国王陛下乐意花一"小"笔钱
Do you truly imagine his majesty will be happy to spend a small fortune
就为了这么"大"场面的鸡飞狗跳 ？
on such a large shambles!?
刚那枪谁打的？
Who fired that musket ball?
应该是我吧 康尼士先生 阁下
I think I did, mr.Cornish, sir.
你想干嘛？
What are you trying to do?
你要是娱乐不了特使们 你就直接朝他们开枪好了
If you can't entertain the envoys, then you're going to shoot them instead!
是这样的吗？嗯？
Is that it?! Hmm?
再来
Again!
我有事让你做 查尔斯
I have some business for you, charles.
谨遵吩咐
As you desire.
我要把妹妹玛格丽特 许配给葡萄牙国王
My sister margaret is to marry the king of portugal.
我要你护送她和嫁妆至里斯本
I want you to escort her and her dowry to lisbon,
代表我送她出嫁
and give her away in my name.
为什么是我？
Why me?
我要能放心的人来做
I need someone I can trust.
你把一个漂亮女人放心交给我？
You trust me with a beautiful woman?
把我妹妹交给你
With my sister.
我当然放心
Of course I trust you.
为什么不放心？
Why shouldn't I?
不管怎么样 你都已经订婚了…
In any case, you're already betrothed to...
跟谁来着？一时记不起
what's her name? I can't keep up.
伊丽莎白-格雷
Elizabeth grey.
她是多塞特侯爵的堂妹
She's the cousin of the marquess of dorset.
正是
Exactly.
能受陛下信任深感荣幸 但还有一个问题
I'm honoured by your majesty's trust but there is still a difficulty.
以我卑微的身份怎可为国王的妹妹送嫁
I'm not important enough to give away the sister of a king
更别说是英格兰国王的妹妹
let alone the king of england.
所以我将封你为公爵
That's why I'm making you a duke.
萨福克公爵
Duke of suffolk.
如何啊大人 满意吗？
How does that please your grace?
快啊
Come on!
皇帝向国王致以最美好的祝愿
The emperor sends his best wishes to the king.
我们非常感谢您 摩尔先生 谢谢您亲自迎接我们
We are most grateful to you, mr.More, for coming to welcome us in person.
不 这是我的荣幸
No, it's my honour.
国王陛下把二位的到访 当作伟大的时刻一般看待
His majesty regards your visit as a thing of great moment.
我们何时得以会见国王陛下呢？
When shall we have an audience with his majesty?
我给二位阁下一句建议
Let me advise your excellencies on this:
只有一条路能传达意向至国王耳中
There is only one way to reach the king's ear,
那就是通过沃尔西主教的协助
and that is through the good offices of cardinal wolsey.
有传言说 摩尔先生 主教他比较维护法国的利益
We heard some rumours, mr.More, that the cardinal advocates french interests.
只有他认为 那些也是我们的利益时才会这样
Only when he considers them to be in ours.
请告诉我 皇帝陛下对路德异教
Tell me: What is the emperor's attitude
在他领土上的崛起有何态度？
to the rise of the lutheran heresy in some of his territories?
我朋友伊拉斯默斯告诉我 在德国 这个异教有着燎原之势
My friend erasmus tells me that in germany it's spreading like a forest fire.
殿下用尽全力镇压这股势力
His highness does everything in his power to suppress it.
但如您所知 路德本人 是德国王子们的客人之一
But, as you know, luther himself is the guest of one of the german princes
很不幸地 超出他的掌控之外
unfortunately beyond his control.
我国王正撰写一本小册子 抨击路德那些邪恶言论
My king is writing a pamphlet demolishing luther's arguments,
保卫教皇制度和我们的信仰
defending the papacy and our faith.
你是说 他亲自动笔写 亲手书写这本书？不可能
You mean, he is writing it himself, with his own hand?No!
我国王所能之事不计其数
There are a great many things that my king can do.
罗马皇帝特使到 主教阁下
The envoys from the emperor, your eminence.
二位阁下
Your excellencies.
有朋自远方来 不亦乐乎
This is indeed a happy day.
为了表示对你们的来访热烈欢迎 我们准备了许多庆典活动
We have planned many festivities in honour of this most welcome visit.
我诚挚的希望
And it is my devout hope and wish
我们能共同完成协议的细节
that together, we can finalize the details of a treaty
这协议将使得我们两国的君主 友谊长存
which will bind your master and mine in perpetual friendship.
我们也如此衷心希望 主教阁下
That is very much our hope too, your eminence.
好的 请
Good, please.
你别来 托马斯
Not you, thomas.
我不想浪费二位和我自己的时间
I don't want to waste your time, or mine.
在畅饮之前 请告诉我
So before we drink, tell me:
皇帝陛下对这协议是否真诚？
Is the emperor in fact sincere about this treaty?
- 毫无疑问是的 - 那好
-  Of course he is. -  Good.
我一定尽力巩固这项大事
Then I propose to cement it.
同时我们将宣布 将我国王之女
We also announce the betrothal of the emperor
玛丽公主 许配皇帝陛下
to the daughter of the king, princess mary.
据我们理解 公主已经与法国皇太子订婚
It is our understanding that she is already betrothed to the dauphin.
但现在她被许给查尔斯殿下了
But now she will be betrothed to charles.
除非二位有异议？
Unless you have some other objection?
- 并没有 - 好极了
-  On the contrary. -  Good.
那么共识达成
We are agreed.
皇帝陛下…
The emperor...
命我们私下转告主教阁下
told us to inform your eminence personally
希望您能接受他赠予您的 非常丰厚的一笔抚恤
that he wishes to bestow upon you a very generous pension.
他亦将全力支持您当上教皇的雄心
He will also throw his weight behind your ambitions to be pope.
为二位阁下成功来访干杯
Let us drink to the success of your excellencies' visit.
一定
By all means.
找到方法让我甥女出现在国王眼前了？
You have found some means to put my niece before the king?
是的 大人 都安排好了
Yes, your grace. Already arranged.
安 会出现在给特使安排的表演中
Anne is to appear in the pageant for the spanish envoys.
国王陛下也会
As is the king.*Framlinghan Castle, A Residence of the Duke of Norfolk*
她会有办法吸引他注意的
She will find a way to draw his attention.
好啊
Good!
当她为他张开双腿 就能张嘴除掉沃尔西
When she opens her legs for him, she can open her mouth and denounce wolsey.
的确有种说法 最锋锐的利刃藏在最柔软的袋子里
They do say that the sharpest blades are sheathed in the softest pouches.
红衣主教沃尔西阁下及西班牙大使 门多萨和查姆普伊斯大人到
His eminence, cardinal wolsey and the spanish ambassadors mendoza and champuis.
那些女士们是什么人？
Who are those ladies?
她们是美德女神 阁下
They are the graces,excellence.
她们名叫善 荣 坚 慈及悯
They have names like kindness, honour,constance,mercy and pity.
她们被囚禁在城堡中
They are prisoners in the castle.
左边那位 站在破碎的心下方的
The figure to the left, under the broken hearts
便是国王陛下的妹妹 玛格丽特公主
is his majesty's sister, princess margaret.
是谁囚禁了她们？
Who is keeping them prisoner?
险
Danger.
妒
Jealousy.
恶
Unkindness.
嘲
Scorn.
鄙 怪 等等…
Disdain. Strangeness...
国王也在其中？
Is the king there?
是哪一位？
Which one is the king?
男人们代表年轻 奉献 忠诚 意志
The men represent youth,devotion, loyalty,pleasure.
风度… 自由
Gentleness...liberty!
并且是的 国王陛下就隐藏其中
And,yes,his majesty is hid amongst them.
作为热望之化身 我要求你们释放被囚之人
As ardent desire, I demand you release your prisoners!
作为嘲之女神 我嘲笑你的热望
As lady scorn,I laugh at your desires.
你眼前的男士们都是显赫的贵族
These men are noble lords.
不 他们只是盛装的普通人
No,they're just men dressed up!
我重复一次
I say it again:
放了这些 被如此残酷囚禁的美好少女
Release these fair damsels that you keep so cruelly.
休想
Never.
那么我们别无选择 只有攻击
You give us no choice but to attack,
撕裂你们的防御
and breach your defenses!
任何骑士都不可能撕裂我的"防御"
No knight shall ever breach mine.
女士 热望压倒一切
Lady,desire overcomes all!
攻击
Attack!
坚守女神 你是我的囚犯了
Perseverance, you are my prisoner now.
王妹
Sister.
王兄
Brother.
现在 全体取下面罩
And now all shall be unmasked.
我得跟你谈谈
I must speak to you.
我相信你已经处理好你那些关系了 玛格丽特
I trust you've settled all your affairs here,margaret.
是的 但…
Yes,but...
(葡萄牙)国王已经来信 表达对你的爱慕
the king has written of his love for you...
见过你的画像后 更迫不及待想见你真人一面
and has eagerness to set eyes on you, having seen your portrait.
求你 我是你妹妹 别把我嫁给那个人
I plead with you,as your sister, don't make me marry him.
他那么老了
He's an old man!
你是谁？
Who are you?
我是安-博林
Anne boleyn.
谢谢 康尼士大师
Thank you,master cornish.
非常感谢你
I'm very grateful to you.
托马斯大人…
Sir,thomas...
能与你的主子见面吗？
may I see your mistress?
一位先生求见 殿下
A gentleman,my lady.
布兰登先生
Mr.Brandon.
我想你还没有荣升公爵吧？
You are not yet invested a duke, I think?
还没有 殿下
No,madam.
我要带200随从到葡萄牙去
I shall be taking with me,to portugal, a company of 200 persons.
包括我的管家 牧师 洗衣工 还有我所有侍女
They shall include my chamberlain,my chaplain, my laundress,all of my ladies.
是 殿下
Yes,madam.
还有任何事情需要讨论的 你可以跟管家谈
Should you have anything to discuss, you may do so with my chamberlain.
是 殿下
Yes,madam.
我很惊讶 王兄居然选了一位 没有贵族血统的人来代表他
I am surprised my brother chose a man without noble blood to represent hiM.
就算是诺福克都好些
Even norfolk would have been better.
佩斯先生 王后陛下准备好会见了
Mr.Pace,the queen is ready.
请待我通报王后二位的到来
I will announce you to the queen.
阿拉贡的凯瑟琳陛下 英格兰王后
Her majesty katherine of aragon, queen of england.
陛下 西班牙特使到
Your majesty,the envoys from spain.
我知道你们跟国王约定了会见
I konw you have an audience with the king
我只是无法错过与你们见面的机会
I just couldn't let you pass without seeing you
陛下
Majesty
您的侄儿 罗马帝国皇帝 向您传达对您的爱及长久的祝愿
your nephew the emperor sends you his love and fillial regards always
跟他说 如果他爱我
Tell him, if he loves me
就该多些来信
he should write to more often
但我从心底感到欢乐
but I happy from the bottom of my heart
你们能来这里
that you are here
能够签订一项和平协议
and that there is going to be a treaty
当心红衣主教
just beware the Cardinal
国王陛下即刻接见二位大人
His majesty will receive you now.
先生们 欢迎来到我的王国
Gentlemen,welcome to my kingdom.
我知道两位的努力谈判会成功 一项圆满的协议将会达成
I know you will succeed in your efforts to negotiate a successful treaty.
请相信红衣主教沃尔西的每句话
You may trust everything cardinal wolsey says.
在所有事项上 他是我的直接代言人
He speaks for me directly in all matters.
作为我本人 我希望邀请皇帝陛下来访
As for my part I should like to invite the emperor to visit here,
越快越好
as soon as can be arranged.
他的来访将会给我 我的王后 带来无上的喜悦
The visit would give pleasure both to me, to my queen.
陛下
Your majesty.
他几时来？
When's he coming?
本月末
The end of this month.
这么快？
So soon?
若是他需要攻打法兰西的盟友
If he needs allies for his attack on the french,
那即是说有意在近期进攻
that can only mean he intends to do so very shortly.
没错
Indeed.
使节私下告诉我
The envoys told me in confidence
西班牙国王将首先进攻法占意大利
that the emperor will strike first against the french occupation in italy.
他持米兰公国的所有权
He has a claim to the duchy of milan.
然后呢？
And then?
在您的帮助下 将法国人逐出意大利后
Then,having driven them out of italy, with your help
他将攻打法国本土
he will invade france itself.
集结所有军队参加联合进攻
I want you to prepare all our forces for a joint invasion.
遵命 阁下
Yes,your majesty.
还有 再造一艘军舰
And I want another warship.
阁下 凯旋号才下水不久
Majesty,we have only just launched the victory.
下单再造一艘 一艘更大的
Then order another one,a greater one.
缺少士兵 可用战船替代
What we lack in men we can more than make up for in ships.
主教 我们是岛国民族
We're an island race,cardinal.
拥有着世界上最优秀最勇敢的海员
We have the best and bravest sailors in the world.
我要造一支最强的海军
I will have the greatest navy!
军舰花费昂贵
Ships are expensive.
我父亲是个谨慎的人
My father was a careful man.
精明的人
A shrewd man.
更是个商人
A businessman.
他留给我一大笔财产 主教阁下
He left me a great deal of money, your eminence.
我准备尽其所用
I intend to spend it.
很好
Good.
托马斯-博林爵士
Sir thomas boleyn.
托马斯爵士
Sir thomas.
陛下
Majesty.
来
Come.
我自觉有些怠慢
I feel I have been a little remiss.
对于你为我做出的外交上的努力 我从未表示感激
I never showed my gratitude for all the diplomatic efforts you made on my behalf.
陛下何需此言
Your majesty had no need.
我悉听陛下吩咐 尽我所能为您效劳
I am simply content to serve you, in whatever capacity I can be of use.
尽管如此 还是要表示我的感激
Nevertheless, I wish to share my gratitude.
我愿封你为嘉德爵士
It pleases me to make you a knight of the garter.
同时钦点你为王室的财务审检
I am also appointing you comptroller of my household.
恐怕陛下高估了鄙人的才能
I believe your majesty has a greater opinion of my talents than I have.
这当由我来决定
I shall be the judge of that.
迟些再议
We shall talk more later.
噢 差点忘了
Oh. I almost forgot.
你的女儿
Your daughter.
参演了化装舞会的那个？
The one who performed in our masquerade?
安
Anne.
正是
Yes.
事实上 她很快便会入宫
As a matter of fact, she is soon to come to court,
做皇后陛下的侍女
as a ladyinwaiting to her majesty.
西弗城堡 博林一家居所
Hever Castle Boleyn Family Home
你将离我如此而去？
And will you leave me thus?
非 非 多么遗憾
Say nay,say nay,for shame.
换用我的悲叹 拯救你于责难？
To save you from the blame, of all my grief and grame?
而你将离我这般而去？
And will you leave me so?
不 不
Say no,say no.
而你将离我如此而去
And will you leave me thus
心中无处容他爱你？
and have no more pity of he that loves thee?
唉 残忍的你
Alas,your cruelty.
而你将离我这般而去？
And will you leave me thus?
不 不
Say no,say no.
嗯… 喜欢吗？
Well...do you like it?
难道我该喜欢谴责我残忍的词段吗？
Should I like something that accuses me of being cruel?
你真残忍 安女士
You are cruel,mistress anne.
是吗？
Am I?
你不能这么做 怀亚特先生
You have no claim on me,master wyatt.
我对所有的情人都是如此说的
I have the same claim as every other lover,
女人心天生自由
to whom a woman's heart has been freely given.
你是诗人 就如我是女人
You are a poet,as I am a woman.
诗人和女人的心总是自由的 不是吗？
Poets and women are always free with their hearts,are they not?
安
Anne.
停下 汤姆
Stop it,tom!
你不能这样
You mustn'T.
看来我是对的了？
Then I was right?
你意已绝 将离我而去
You are leaving me.
怎么不回答？
Why don't you answer me?
你结婚了
You're married.
没错 但是我们分居了
Yes,but I'm separated.
我就要离婚
I'm going to divorce.
再说 有谁不是结婚了的？
I mean,who isn't married?
今后不要再想来见我
You must never ask to see me again.
你能保证吗？
Do you promise?
为什么？
Why should I?
我明白这保证没什么意义
When I have just learned what promises are worth.
有别人了对吗？
Is it another?
对不对？
Is that it?
你爱上了别人？
Do you love another?
别再来找我
Never ask of me,and never,
如果你自重的话 别对别人提及我
if you value your life, speak of me to others.
明白了吗？
Do you understand?
你就毫无怜悯之心？
Have you no pity?
你想象得出来吗？
Can you imagine?
想象他现在会怎样
Imagine what he's gonna be like now.
我打赌他下体已经按耐不住
I'll wager he's already ordered a bigger codpiece!
是 阁下
Yes,your grace.
不 阁下
No,your grace.
让我收集你的屁去换美酒 阁下
Let me bottle up your farts and sell them for nectar,your grace.|不 阁下|No,your grace.
Let me bottle up your farts and sell them for nectar,your grace.
我不要再想了
I don't want to think about it any more.
想起了都难受
It makes me ill.
那我们干吗好？
So what shall we do?
找姑娘
Find women.
就算她是纯洁无暇的女神
Even if she was a complete venus,
我这么垂头丧气 也满足不了她
I couldn't satisfy her in my dejected state.
我们就多喝点酒吧
Let's just drink more then.
好啊
Alright.
敬阁下
To his grace.
敬查尔斯
Here's to charles.
阁下
His grace.
使节是否载着好消息回去了？
Did the envoys leave in good cheer?
他们满怀欣喜
They were in excellent spirits.
条约已经签署
The treaty is agreed.
我的侄子会来吗？
And my nephew will come?
等待消息吧
We wait for news.
沃尔西会知道的
Wolsey will find out.
我做了个梦
I had a dream.
在梦里 你又来找我
In my dream,you came to me again,
将我拥在怀中
and held me in your arms,
轻声说一切都安好 万事都安好
and you whispered that all would be well and all manner of things would be well.
亨利
Henry.
亲爱的
Sweetheart.
丈夫
Husband.
你一定要相信我
You must believe me.
我从未那般的… 亲近过你的皇兄
I never knew your brother,in that way.
他当时那么年轻
He was so young.
那么虚弱
And he was ill.
我从未亲近其他男人
I have never known another man,
也不想亲近其他男人
nor ever want to.
我爱你
I love you.
国王陛下驾到
The king!
去房间里见国王
Won't you join the king in his chambers?
玛丽
Mary.
我的爱女
My darling daughter.
阳光小姑娘
Miss yellow.
你做祷告了吗？
Have you said your prayers?
做了
Yes.
陛下
My lord.
这样您喜欢吗？
How like you this?
国王可有什么消息或者迹象说 今晚可能会来看我？
Has the king sent any message or sign that he might visit me tonight?
没有 殿下
No,my lady.
我很担心你 亲爱的
Oh,worried about you,my love.
你工作得太辛苦
You work too hard.
我知道
I know that.
这样会让你丧命
It will kill you.
我也知道
I know that too.
那我该怎么办？
What am I supposed to do?
活下去
Stay alive.
你不来吗？
Aren't you coming?
怎么回事？
What's happening?
皇后的新侍女到了
The queen's new ladies have arrived.
来啊
Come on!
小姐
Mistress!
看看她走路的样子…
The way she carries herself...
"这就如剧毒的毒蛇一般 竟然把圣城罗马称作巴比伦
"What serpent was ever so venomous as to call the holy city of rome babylon...
把教皇的权威称作暴政
and the pope's authority tyranny,
把神圣的神父蔑称为反基督徒？"
turned the name of our holy father into antichrist?"
很好
It's very good.
言辞激烈 但是很好
Strongly worded,but it's very good.
你确定？
You're sure?
也许言辞可以稍微温和一些
Well you might think of toning down the polemic just a little.
比如你把路德叫做"杂种"的这地方 到哪儿去了？
For example,where you describe luther as "this weed",where is it?
这里 "这丧心病狂的孬种"
"This dilapidated, sick and evilminded sheep."
温和一点？
Tone it down?
是啊 出于…
Well yes,for...
出于外交策略
for diplomatic purposes.
不 不行
No,never.
谴责路德怎么说都不过分
No language can be strong enough to condemn luther,
赞扬他却是无话可说
nor gracious enough to praise his holiness.
我会为他准备一份副本
I will dedicate a copy to him,
你到罗马去交给他
and you will take it to him,in rome.
为什么是我？
Why me?
如果其中有任何一丝真善之处 都是因为你
If there is anything true and good in it, it is due to you.
如果没有你的指导和忠诚 托马斯-摩尔爵士
I could never have written it or anything else, sir thomas more,
我是永远也无法写出此慷慨之言
without your guidance and unfailing honesty.
您为什么叫我托马斯爵士？
Why do you call me sir thomas?
我所能做的 只能是你封爵
A knighthood is the least I could do.
我所做的还不值得如此
It's a great deal more than I deserve.
不要太谦逊了 托马斯
Now,don't be too modest,thomas.
你不是圣人
You're not a saint.
我还有别的事要托付你
There is something else I want you to do for me.
收缴所有能找到的路德的作品
Seize all the copies of luther's works you can find
烧掉
and burn them.
全部烧掉
Burn them all.
法国来信
From france.
弗朗西斯国王已经发现
Well,king francis has already discovered
我们和西班牙恢复邦交了
our rapprochement with the emperor.
他觉得被背叛 很生气 并为此威胁我们
He feels betrayed and angry and is making threats against our interests.
谁告诉他的？
Who told him?
圣保罗十字街 伦敦
*********
阿门
Amen.
女士们先生们
My lords and ladies,
圣罗马帝国皇帝 阿拉贡 巴伦西亚
his imperial highness,charles,holy roman emperor,
那不勒斯及西西里之国王 查尔斯殿下
king of aragon,valencia,naples and sicily.
勃艮第公爵
Duke of burgundian territories.
奥地利大公
Archduke of austria.
主教阁下 稍等
Your eminence,a moment.
走开 佩斯先生
Move away,mr.Pace.
走开
Move away.
遵命 主教阁下
Yes,eminence.
殿下
Your highness!
陛下
Your majesty!
我没料到…
I did not expect...
我忍受不了等待
I could not sustain the anticipation.
所以直接下来迎接您
I had to come straight down and welcome you myself.
我真是万分荣幸
Then I am truly honoured.
欢迎
Bienvenidos.
今晚我们就跳舞狂欢吧
Tonight we shall dance and feast.
明天 带你去看看我的舰队
And tomorrow,you shall come see my ships.
先生们
Gentlemen.
奏乐
Music!
庆祝吧
Let's celebrate!
来
Come.
把那个人带走
Remove that man.
等一下
Wait.
不 等一下
No,wait.
等一下
Wait!
啊 佩斯先生
Ah,mr.Pace.
你一定获悉国王陛下的突然来访
You knew,of course,that his majesty was going to make this surprise visit
对吗？
did you not?
没错
Well yes.
我是他的秘书 当然知道
As his secretary I would obviously know.
是啊 你当然知道
Yes,of course you did.
当然你也知道
And you also knew of course,
皇帝的特使曾经秘密到访 想和陛下签署条约
that the imperial envoys had come,privately, to make a treaty with his majesty.
当然 你也说西班牙文 不是吗？
But then of course, you speak spanish,don't you?
如你的法文一样流利
Almost as well as you speak french.
我 呃…
I uh...
我不明白主教大人您的意思
I don't understand your eminence.
我认为你心知肚明 佩斯先生
I think you do,mr.Pace.
我真得如此认为
I really think you do.
因为你看 我认为
Because you see,I think
你不单替我做眼线 你还替法国人做间谍
you not only spy for me you also spy for the french.
不 不是这样的
No.It's not true!
你的所有职务将被撤销
You are removed from all your positions.
别 等等 等等 等等
No,wait! Wait!Wait!
我向您发誓
I swear to you.
我以一切圣明发誓 那不是真的
I swear by everything that's holy it's not true!
我对陛下赤胆忠心
His majesty is held dear in my heart.
密谋反对陛下 此乃叛国之罪
It is treason to plot against his majesty.
等等
Wait.
您到底什么意思？
What are you saying?
主教大人 等等 求您了
Wait your eminence,please!
别这样对我
Don't do this!
您知道这不是真的
You know it's not true!
求您了 主教大人
Your eminence please!
我恳求您
I beg you!
您知道这不是真的 主教大人 求您了
You know it's not true, your eminence,please!
求求您
Please!
这是我的旗舰 玛丽-罗斯号
This is my flagship,the mary rose.
是我旗下最庞大一艘战舰
She's the largest warship afloat.
可运载重达七百吨 内置91樽大炮
She displaces 700 tons,fires 91 guns,
以及四百人的武装
and has a company of 400 men.
我可没有这样的装备
I have nothing like this.
您有庞大的军队
You have vast armies.
你我联手 所向无敌
Together,we shall be invincible.
法国人怎能与我们匹敌
How could the french withstand us?
有您与我并肩作战
With you beside me,
没有任何一个边界 前线 甚至是世界 是我们无法攻破的
there is no boundary or frontier or world we could not conquer.
我已经对您格外倾心
I like you already.
除了我的下巴 还有什么不讨您的欢心？
Except for the chin what is there not to like?
叛徒门 伦敦塔
Traitor's gate tower of london
囚犯上岸
Prisoner to the steps!
您一定要相信我
You must believe me.
我是无辜的
I'm an innocent man.
我不知道为什么会被带到这里
I don't know why I've been brought here.
我是无辜的
I'm innocent!
不 不 不
No! No! No!
我什么也没有做错
I've done nothing wrong!
我没有做过任何错事
要知道 你和我之间 被不可割断的纽带紧紧相连
You know,you and I are united by an indissoluble tie.
您娶了我母亲的妹妹 您就是我的叔父
since you married my mother's sister, you are really my uncle.
这是段让我欣喜欢愉的连理 侄子
It's an affinity which both delights and pleases me,nephew.
殿下 您的阿姨正在等候您
Your highness,your aunt awaits.
圣罗马帝国陛下 查尔斯皇帝殿下驾到
Your majesty,his imperial highness, charles,holy roman emperor.
皇后殿下 肯求您赐予我姨侄之间的祝福
Majesty,I ask for your blessing, as a nephew to an aunt.
我亲爱的查尔斯 我所献给你的祝福
I give you my blessing freely,
将如我对你的爱一样滔滔不绝
my dear charles as I give you my love.
殿下 请允许我向您介绍我的女儿玛丽 也就是您未来的新娘
Your highness,allow me to present my daughter mary,your future bride.
好极了
Bravo.
过来
Come!
我们必须经过等待
We must wait.
才能结婚
To be married.
你认为你能有足够的耐心吗？
Do you think you have the patience?
我为殿下您准备了一份礼物
I have a present for your highness.
您想看看吗？
Do you want to see it?
我喜欢礼物
I love presents.
给我看看
Show me!
在那里 您看
There! Look!
那些都是给我的吗？
Are they for me?
您喜欢吗？
Do you like them?
它们是我得到的最好的礼物
They're the best presents I've ever had!
谢谢你 殿下
Thank you,your highness.
您二位可要尽早来探访我
As soon as possible, you must both come and visit me.
我要带您欣赏英勇善战的征服者 阿兹特克族国王
I want to show you especially the treasures of montezuma,king of the aztecs,
在墨西哥发掘的蒙特祖玛宝藏
that general cortez recently discovered in mexico.
我们非常之乐意
We should love that.
是的
Yes.
对于一海之隔的"印度" 我们也略有所闻
We've heard a little about the lands across the sea they call the indies.
我跟您说…
I'll tell you...
我跟您发誓 那就是延续未来的地方
I swear to you, that is where the future lies.
大量未被开发的领土
So much undiscovered land.
无以计数的金银 矿物和盐
So much wealth of gold and silver, of minerals and salts.
皇后夫人
Madam.
甜心
Sweetheart.
尽量在他面前出现
Put yourself in his way.
您的备战准备得如何？
How are your preparations going?
我们加大征召德国雇佣兵
We are recruiting more german mercenaries.
一切都算顺利
But everything is going well.
来年春天 我们将攻下米兰
I shall take milan by next spring.
然后呢？
And then?
然后…
And then...
你我 将联军入侵法国
together,we shall invade france
断送掉弗朗西斯国王的 放荡君主冒险之旅
and bring to an end the adventures of that libertine monarch,king francis.
那会让我欣喜若狂
That will make me very happy.
还会让您成为法国国王
It will also make you king of france!
是的
Yes.
精彩 精彩
Bravo! Bravo!
再来一支舞 再来一支
Encore! Encore!
殿下 能否共舞？
Will you dance,your highness?
哦 当然还要经过陛下您的批准
With your majesty's permission.
准
Granted.
失陪
Excuse me.
我听说葡萄牙国王还有痛风
The king of portugal, I've heard he also has gout.
人说他的脊椎已经变形
They say his spine is deformed.
走路好像螃蟹一样
He walks like a crab.
皇兄 请应承我一件事
Promise me something brother.
要我同意下嫁 有一个条件
I'll agree to marry him on one condition:
他死后… 反正也是不远的事 我的婚嫁对象将由我来选择
When he's dead,which can't be long I can marry whom I choose!
您同意吗？
Agreed?
今天不喝酒了吗 查尔斯？
Not drinking today,charles?
我还是该称你为大人？
Or should I say,your grace?!
看你还是称其本名 浪子或是流氓
You should definitely call him by his real name which is cunt,or villain.
为什么？
Why?
我们本该是朋友 查尔斯
We're supposed to be friends,charles.
我们现在不是朋友了吗？
Aren't we,still?
如果你不给我们少少好处 就没的朋友可做
Not if you don't show us favour.
得到赏赐的你 有义务请求陛下赐予我们头衔
It's within your gift to ask his majesty to give us some titles,
或至少封赏给我们些土地
or at least some land.
看来国王的赏赐 全部都落入了你的口袋
Seems everything the king has to give he's given to you already!
你们嫉妒？
Jealous?
理所应当的事
Naturally.
你高升 我们也该高升
As you rise,so too should we.
我们有什么能为您效劳的 大人？
So what can we do for you,your grace?
尊重我
Show me some respect!
精彩
Bravo.
回到你的座位上
Back to your seat.
能见到您我很高兴
I am so glad to see you.
这里总是一片寂寥
It is often lonely here.
寂寥？
Lonely?
陛下和我之间
Things are not well between us.
相处得并不好
His majesty and I.
但是…
But...
我亲眼看到他对您是多么的倾慕
I saw with my own eyes how attentive he is to you.
他看您的时候是如此全心投入
He looks at you with such,devotion.
如此充满了爱意
It seems with such love.
恐怕那是给您看的
I fear that is for your benefit.
亨利很会伪装
Henry is a good masquer.
别再让我听到你那番话
I don't want to hear this again.
安女士？
Lady anne?
在 陛下
Yes,your majesty.
我觉得 他终有一天会同我离婚
I think sometimes he will ask me for a divorce.
离婚？
A divorce!?
不 那没可能
No,that's impossible.
是吗？
Is it?
请原谅
Forgive me.
安
Anne.
不 不要这样
No.Not like this.
那要怎样？
How?
引诱我
Seduce me.
致我于书信
Write letters to me.
和诗词
And poems.
我热爱诗词
I love poems.
用你的文字夺走我的心
Ravish me with your words.
引诱我
Seduce me.
陛下
Majesty!
没事
It's alright.
她走了
She's gone.
敬请两位陛下 以封印来见证两国所签订的
For your majesties to sign between you this treaty of perpetual amity and concord,
永久友好共处条约 并在此诸多王公贵族见证下
and to confirm with your seals and before these witnesses
并认可 于玛丽公主殿下年长于12岁之际
the betrothal of charles, holy roman emperor,
下嫁于圣罗马帝国皇帝查尔斯
and her highness princess mary, upon her reaching the age of 12.
我将以教廷使节 及英格兰 商议大臣的身份 再次向您们重申
I say to you again,in my power as papal legate and chancellor of england,
您们将在这 验证彼此相敬相爱的合约上签字
that you should sign this treaty of friendship,one to another,
永不毁约 愿上帝保佑
and never break it,so help you god.
我想您保证我对您的敬慕和忠诚
I swear to you my honour and allegiance.
请您永远给予我于信任
You must always trust in me.
永远
Always.
佩斯先生呢？
Where is mr. Pace?
他应该参加才对
He should have been here.
陛下 我极为愧疚的发现
Your majesty, I have discovered,shamefully,
佩斯先生玷污了陛下您对他的信任
that mr.Pace was not deserving your majesty's trust.
我已经将他从职位上撤走
I have removed him from his offices.
你确定？
You're sure?
法国人用重金将其收买
The french were paying him a pension.
我明白了
I see.
相信你能替我找人取而代之
I trust you'll find me a replacement.
我说 我们的事情进展如何？
Well? How do our affairs proceed?
非常顺利 大人
Very well,your grace.
国王还没有言明对她的倾心
The king makes no obvious declaration of interest
但通过他看她的眼神 可以洞察出
but it's possible to detect it in the way he glances at her
在他的思绪中 他已对她的裸体垂涎许久
as if,in his mind,he could see her naked.
那倒是 但他看很多年轻女人都是用那种目光
Yes,well,he looks at most young women that way.
但这只是个开始
But it is a start.
推倒那个 让人难以忍受的教士的一个开始
A beginning at least to the end of that insufferable prelate.
时机刚刚好
All in good time.
一切将接踵而来
One thing will follow another.
或许将萨福克公爵列入我们的计划中 也是个明智之举
Perhaps it would be a good idea to include the duke of suffolk in our plans.
查尔斯-布兰登 ？
Charles brandon!?
他可不是什么君子
He is barely a gentleman.
他是皇帝最亲近的朋友
He's the king's closest friend.
相信他和我们一样憎恨沃尔西
And I believe hates wolsey as much as we do.
至少在这多事之秋
He would be a natural ally.
大家都是同道中人
At least for a time!
攻击得分
Attack!
安东尼-墨尔本先生夺得两分
Two points for mr.Anthony melbourne.
海斯先生
Mr. Heys,
我要的你带来了吗？
do you have those pieces I asked for?
是的 陛下
Yes,your majesty.
黄金镶边红宝石一枚
One,rubies set in circlets of gold.
镶于黄金与珍珠簇拥之下的 稀有宝石一枚
Second,a precious stone upon a bed of gold and pearl.
带有黄金紫石及狮头装饰的
A third,small and large drops of pearl, with gold and purple
什锦珍珠一幅
and the detail of a lion's head.
最后 由金银琥珀铸造的羽饰
And lastly feathers of silver, gold and amber.
这些珠宝很适合皇后殿下 陛下
Jewels fit for a queen,your majesty.
是沃尔西
It was wolsey!
不是我
Not me!
听我说
Listen to me.
收取法国人赃款的是沃尔西
It's wolsey who has a pension from the french.
不是我
Not me!
听我说
Listen to me!
我什么都没做
I didn't do anything!
我是无辜的
I'm innocent!
是沃尔西 沃尔西 沃尔西
It was wolsey! Wolsey! Wolsey!
去质问他 质问他
Just ask him! Ask him!
是沃尔西
It was wolsey!